Guide to the Stanford Historical Society, Historic Houses III, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Historical Society, Historic Houses III, records
1972-2004
1999-2004
SC0760
Stanford Historical Society.
2 Linear feet
Research and production materials for the book, HISTORIC HOUSES III: SAN JUAN NEIGHBORHOOD, STANFORD UNIVERSITY, published by the Stanford Historical Society in 2005. Includes Byron Feig's original watercolor painting used on the cover and his original pencil drawings of each house; and copies of architectural drawings for several of the houses featured in the book.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
Research and production materials for the book, HISTORIC HOUSES III: SAN JUAN NEIGHBORHOOD, STANFORD UNIVERSITY, published by the Stanford Historical Society in 2005. Includes Byron Feig's original watercolor painting used on the cover and his original pencil drawings of each house; and copies of architectural drawings for several of the houses featured in the book.
Access Terms
Feig, Byron.; Stanford Historical Society.; Architecture, Domestic--California--Stanford.
Collection Contents
- Research & Production Materials
  - Branner, John K. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clark, Birge (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Sumner, Charles K. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1040 Campus Drive (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1050 Campus Drive (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 743 Cooksey Lane (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 743 Cooksey Lane, photographs (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 421 El Escarpado Way (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 430 El Escarpado Way (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 445 El Escarpado Way (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 450 El Escarpado Way (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 440 Gerona Road (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 536 Gerona Road (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 548 Gerona Road (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 593 Gerona Road (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 593 Gerona Road, photographs (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 607 Gerona Road (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 635 Gerona Road (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 635 Gerona Road, interviews on audiocassettes (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 635 Gerona Road, biographical information (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 792 Santa Maria Avenue (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 740 Santa Ynez (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 740 Santa Ynez, photographs (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 747 Santa Ynez (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 755 Santa Ynez (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 755 Santa Ynez, photographs (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Computer files: 792 Santa Maria history (1 floppy) and photos 548 Gerona, 740 Santa Ynez, 755 Santa Ynez (1 CD-R) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Original watercolor by Byron Feig used for the cover of the book (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Original pencil drawings of individual houses by Byron Feig: Campus Drive, Cooksey Lane (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Original pencil drawings of individual houses by Byron Feig: El Escarpado (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Original pencil drawings of individual houses by Byron Feig: Gerona (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Original pencil drawings of individual houses by Byron Feig: Santa Maria, Santa Ynez (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1040 Campus Drive (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1050 Campus Drive (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 743 Cooksey Lane (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 421 El Escarpado Way (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 430 El Escarpado Way (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 445 El Escarpado Way (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 450 El Escarpado Way (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 440 Gerona Road (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 536 Gerona Road (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 548 Gerona Road (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 593 Gerona Road (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 607 Gerona Road (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 635 Gerona Road (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 792 Santa Maria Avenue (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 740 Santa Ynez (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 747 Santa Ynez (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 755 Santa Ynez (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Drafts, 9/04 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Draft of entire text, 4/3/05 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Draft of entire text, 4/7/05 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence (emails) and source materials (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Computer files (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Map Case items:
    - Drawings (copies) for 755 Santa Ynez: 2 floor plans, 2 elevations
    - Drawings (copies) for 740 Santa Ynez: 7 drawings
    - Drawings (copies) for 743 Cooksey Lane: 1 original design, 1 from 1966 remodel
    - Drawings (copies) for 548 Gerona Rd., Prof. Graham H. Stuart's residence